

Serena Tomassetti

🛱 15th April 1989

O Zürich, Switzerland

் L'Aquila, Italy

C-Permit

CONTACTS

\$\\$ +41 76 728 42 70

□ serenatomassetti001@gmail.com

serenatomassetti.com

in linkedin.com/in/serena-tomassetti

SKILLS

HCI, User Research, User Interface, Wireframing, Rapid Prototyping, Information Architecture, UX Writings, Lean UX, Usability Test.

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Figma, Sketch, Invision, Axure, Balsamiq, Creative Cloud, Zeplin, Google Analytics, Look Back.

LANGUAGES

Italian: native

English: fluent (C1)

German: professional (B2)

PASSIONATE ABOUT

Design, art, photography, skiing, hiking, traveling.

SUMMARY

Resourceful User Experience Designer with broad practice in design and customer experience. I promote a user centered approach across companies and build fruitful relationships with clients and colleagues. I am recognized for critical thinking, accuracy to details, self management and capacity to adapt quickly. I am a curious person, an hungry reader and traveler, with a high interest in technology and innovation.

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer • Contract

Muume AG, Zürich · Dec 2020 - Feb 2021

Designed digital interfaces for B2B and B2C softwares in 3 break points. Collaborated closely with Head of Design, project managers and developers. Field research. Agile methodology.

UX Designer • Contract

Visit Altopiano, Rome (Remote) • Sep - Nov 2020
Designed touristic mobile app for Visit Altopiano from research up to the implementation. Collaborated closely with stakeholders and developers. Lean approach.

UX Designer • Contract

Bar Voce, Rome (Remote) • Apr - Jun 2020
Designed digital strategy for Bar Voce's safe restart during the Covid-19 pandemic. Collaborated closely with stakeholders and developers. Lean approach.

UX Designer • Freelance

Zürich · Aug 2019 - Present

Designed digital user experiences in various freelance projects.

Brand Ambassador

Lindt & Sprüngli, Zürich • Sep 2018 - Dec 2020 Identification of customer needs and behaviour. Sales and customer experience. Collaborated with marketing bridging observations and proposing solutions. Support on store layout, stock and visual merchandising.

Promoter

M.Prestige Promotions, Zürich • Sep 2017 - Aug 2018
Identification of customer needs and behaviour. Target sales for YSL, Dior, Chanel and customer experience. Trained on customer psychology and behavior from Brand Managers.

Travel Designer

Ed è Subito Viaggi, Rome • Sep 2017 - Aug 2018
Designed tailored travel experiences, established long-term customer loyalty and returning customers. Identification of customer needs, customer experience and support.

EDUCATION

User Experience Nanodegree

Udacity • 2020

Created an end-to-end digital user experience ready to be handed off for development.

- User research for qualitative and quantitative data Analysis and Synthesis of collected data
- Design Sprint Low and High fidelity wireframes and prototype Style guide and Design library
- Usability test and Iterations.

User Experience Bootcamp

Interaction Design Foundation • 2019 - 2020

Designed a Project Management Web app through 1 to 1 mentorship sessions and guidance.

- User Research Design Sprint Sitemap Low and High fidelity wireframes and prototype
- Style guide and Design library.

Bachelor of Art

University of L'Aquila, Italy • 2008 - 2013 Cultural and Environmental Heritage.

Erasmus Exchange

University of Zagreb, Croatia • 2012 - 2013Master's Thesis in History of Architecture.

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- UX Management: Strategy and Tactics, Interaction Design Foundation, 2021.
- Information Visualization: Getting dashboards right, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Gamification: Creating addictive user experiences, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Affordances: Designing intuitive user interfaces, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Accessibility: How to design for all, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Emotional Design: How to make products people will love, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Agile Software Development, University of Minnesota, 2020
- Human Computer Interaction- HCI, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- UI Design Patterns for succesful software, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20
- User Research Methods and Best Practises, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Mobile UX Design, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Design Thinking, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Fundamentals of Graphic Design, typography and storytelling, Californian University of Arts, 2019.
- Store Layout & Visual Merchandising, London University of Arts, 2018
- Travel Experience Design, CTS, 2014.